.和Myles一起学音乐.
.冫          .
.减          .
.减乚       .
.减七       .
.减七和弦.
来看这个简单的和弦进行
Here's a simple chord progression.
听上去不错，但如果我们想让它听起来更加变化时应该怎样呢？
That works just fine, but what if we want to spice this up with a little more movement?
一个简单的做法就是在中间插入一个减七和弦
Well, one easy way of doing that is to throw in a diminished seventh chord.
（不要和半减七和弦搞混）
一个减减七和弦，或者叫减七和弦（也叫减导七和弦），
A fully diminished seventh chord, or just "diminished seventh chord" for short,
结构上即在根音上方叠加三个小三度
is the structure we get when we stack three minor 3rds on top of a root note.
减七和弦听起来黑暗且不稳定
Diminished seventh chords sound extremely dark and unstable.
这些特性很有用——
This means they're actually really useful –
我们可以用它来创造有很强期待感的解决
we can use them to create a strong expectation of resolution.
想象把一个减七和弦作为目标，或者导向一个别的主要和弦
Think of the diminished seventh chord as a way of targeting,
or leading into certain other chords.
最常见的形式就是用减七和弦来解决到其向上半音的和弦
The most common pattern for diminished seventh chords is to resolve up a half-step.
让我们再看一次这个进行
Here's that progression of ours again.
让我们试着插入一个减七和弦来导向 E 小和弦
So let's try inserting a diminished seventh chord that leads up a half-step into the E- chord.
这个例子中，导向减七和弦的和弦也刚巧是向上半音解决到我们的减七和弦
In this particular case, we also happen to be approaching the diminished seventh chord
itself with half-step up motion.
你并不总需要这样做，不过这样听起来的确不错
You don't always have to do it this way, but it does tend to work really well.
另一个有效的减七和弦模式是向下解决半音
Another effective diminished seventh chord pattern is resolving down a half-step.
举个例子
Here's an example.
我们也可以使用减七和弦来导向同主音的其它和弦
We can also approach a chord with a diminished seventh chord built on the same root note.
这在一级（主和弦）和五级和弦（属和弦）中效果更为显著
This works especially well on the I and V chords.
被称为辅助减七和弦（同音共减七和弦）
These are called auxiliary diminished seventh chords.
这是个不错的延时方案用以导向目标和弦，
This is a great technique for delaying resolution to the target chord,
也可以以这种独特形式用来为缓慢的进行添加额外动作
or creating extra harmonic motion in an otherwise static moment.
可见，减七和弦有诸多用途非常实用
So, fully diminished seventh chords are really versatile and useful.
它构成的紧张听感使得其导向的和弦听起来更悦耳
Their extremely tense sound makes the relief of the following chord feel that much sweeter.
当然这里只是一个向你展示无限可能性的一个小小介绍
As always, this is a merely an introduction to a whole world of possibilities,
现在就试试你能够使用它来创造出什么吧
so get experimenting and see what you can come up with.
这里是一些写作提示以边你上手
Here's a little writing prompt to get you started.
编写一个任意风格的和弦进行
Write a chord progression in any style.
使之至少有 8 小节长度，但如果你想的话多长都可以
Make it at least 8 bars long, but feel free to go as long as you want,
然后试着包含如下至少一个减七和弦模式
and try to include at least one of each diminished seventh chord pattern.
想要的话，你也可以加上旋律和额外的改编
You can add a melody and additional arrangement if you want,
但我们主要目的还是去感受这些和弦本身
but the main idea here is just to get a feel for the chords themselves.
把你的作品发到评论区这样大家就都能看看了
Post whatever you come up with in the comments so we can all take a look.
你懂的，分享点子嘛...也许我们能够互相学到一些东西...
You know, we're sharing ideas...maybe we're learning a thing or two from each other...
一定会很棒
it's gonna be great.
如果你喜欢这个视频请（在油管）订阅我的频道
If you enjoyed this video, please subscribe.
也别忘了看看我的 Patreon 页面
Also check out my Patreon page.
这个频道的目的是向世界提供免费的音乐教学视频
The purpose of this channel is to offer free music education to the world,
你的贡献能使之成为可能
and your contributions make that possible.
苟利祸福
祝你好运，玩的开心
good luck, have fun